Let's walk through the journey of WeCart,
我们设想一下 WeCart 的客户旅程
our hypothetical online app for grocery delivery.
WeCart 是我们虚拟的线上购物网站
To track the customer's journey in the online space,
要追踪客户的线上访问足迹
you begin with identifying specific ad platforms such as search engines,
首先 要找到特定的广告平台 例如搜索引擎、
Instagram, Twitter, Facebook, and many others.
Instagram、Twitter、Facebook 等等
This way, the app company can see how many users actually saw the ad.
这些平台可以告诉我们到底有多少用户看到了我们的广告
Next, in the marketing journey,
接着 在营销环节
a viewer who has seen the ad in any of these places will click on the ad.
看到广告的用户会点击相应广告
Great. Now, the viewer is on
然后 界面会转至 WeCart 网站
the WeCart website and a cookie gets placed on the viewers browser.
而用户的浏览器上也会启动 cookie
You've probably encountered cookies when web surfing.
上网的时候 你应该也看到过 cookies
You remember those warnings you get that cookies being placed,
会弹出警示提醒你 如果继续使用当前的网站
if you continue using the website?
就会启动 cookies
Yes, we're talking about that feature.
我们所说的就是那个功能
Once that cookie is placed,
启动 cookie 功能之后
the company is tracking what the potential customer is doing on the website.
公司就可以追踪潜在客户在这个网站上的操作
For example, whether the person is browsing or selecting items for purchase.
例如 潜在客户是仅在浏览页面 还是在挑选要购买的商品 ?
Essentially, it tracks a potential customers progress
基本上 每当潜在客户在网站上操作时
along the customer journey whenever the customer interacts with the website.
cookie 功能就会随时追踪客户在整个访问过程中的足迹
So, now the company's goal is to get
现在 公司的目标变成
this potential customer to do something on the website.
如何让潜在客户在网站上做出某些行为
In the case of WeCart,
对 WeCart 而言
it could be something as simple as getting the customer
可能是希望客户
to give their email address or download a brochure.
留下电子邮箱地址或者下载宣传册
When a customer's action is a result of a prompt it is called Call to Action.
如果客户是因受到提示引导而做出某种行为 则称为 "行为召唤"
So, when the customer is prompted to submit the email,
例如 客户受提示引导而填写电子邮箱
that is referred to as Call to Action or CTA. Next step.
这就称为 "行为召唤" (英文称 Call to Action 或简称 CTA)
If the customer adds items to their cart,
下一步 如果客户添加商品到购物车
the cookie tracks this step in the customer journey to becoming a paid customer.
cookie 会追踪到客户旅程中的这一步 即潜在客户可能会付费
So, now WeCart would want these customers who have
因此 WeCart 现在会希望
added items to the cart to make that purchase,
添加商品到购物车的客户真正下单购买
and finally, the viewer submits the payment details and goes through checkout.
该潜在客户最后要填写付款详情 并完成付款
Now, you have a paid customer and they've completed the customer journey.
这样 他们便完成了一次旅程 你也拿下了一个订单
This customer journey can be described by five stages;
客户旅程可概括为五个阶段 —
Awareness, Interest, Desire, Purchase, and Post-purchase.
获知网站的存在、了解的兴趣、购买的欲望、下单、购买后行为
In each stage, the marketer uses different digital tools to
在各个阶段 营销人员使用不同的数字工具
attract a potential customer and try to transform them into an actual customer.
来吸引潜在客户 努力使其转化为实际客户
This customer journey can also be tracked along
想要追踪客户旅程 还可以借助
a marketing funnel which is a concept we will talk about in the next video.
营销漏斗 我们会在下一个视频中介绍这个概念
The funnel allows you to tie everything together on
营销漏斗能帮助你结合客户旅程中的所有环节
the customer journey and track with a good content along the journey.
在追踪客户旅程的同时 提供直观化表述